Let's dive a little deeper into this analogy of
让我们来深入对比一下
HTML being the basic building block of the web.
为什么说 HTML 是 Web 的基本构成元素
So I have two different metaphors here.
这里我们有两种不同的比喻
The first one is a little squeamish for me,
第一种对我来说要稍微隐晦一些
but I've heard it works for a lot of people.
但是也有很多人认为它很有用
So one way to think about these things is that
第一种比喻方式就是把
HTML is like the skeleton of your webpages.
HTML 看做是 Web 网页的骨架
It's the bones. You might say,
你也可以看做是骨头
I want a head here,
我有一个头部
and I want to shoulder here,
我有一个肩膀
and some legs down here,
下面还有大腿
that would be the skeleton you're building.
一起构成了整个骨架
Then the CSS could be like the skin or I might like clothes that go over it.
而 CSS 就像是你的皮肤或者是你穿的衣服
It's how our head looks,
我头部的样子
and how our legs looks,
腿部的样子
what color they are, what style.
什么颜色 什么风格等等
Then JavaScript can be thought of as the brain.
JavaScript 则可以看做是你的大脑
It sends the functionality that should be done throughout these things.
它给其他部分发送指令来告诉他们需要做什么
So I might have set up my head with HTML and then I might have put
所以我可能已经用 HTML 组装好了我的头部 然后用 CSS
my beautiful red hair on it with CSS and then my brain,
添加了上了酷炫的红色头发 然后 我的大脑
the JavaScript might say,
JavaScript 可能会说
shake your head back and forth like this.
像这样摇晃你的头部
Now, you understand how webpages work.
现在 你应该知道 Web 网页是怎么运行的了
The other way to think about it,
另一种看待它的方式
it's a little more technical and I tend towards this,
则会更偏向技术风格一些 我更喜欢这种
which is to think about the HTML is really the foundation of your website.
也就是把 HTML 看做是你网站的地基
It's almost like if you were making a building,
就好像你准备修建一座建筑
it's the bones of it.
它就是建筑的初始骨架
It's the pieces that are there.
一个个碎片拼图
Then the style is what goes over
然后样式就是我们用来装饰它的元素
those things covered them to make them look like whatever we want.
使它看起来更像我们想要建造的东西
Then the JavaScript handles the functionality and behavior.
JavaScript 则用来负责一些功能和行为
So let me give you an example just with one element.
让我用一个元素来举例
Let's say, we have a P element.
比如 P 元素
That's the paragraph element which we know is HTML.
我们知道它是 HTML 中的段落元素
Then I might want to say,
然后我可能会想
the text for that I want it to be yellow.
我希望文字变成黄色
So that would be CSS.
这就是 CSS 需要做的
So I've added CSS to the HTML.
所以我们把 CSS 添加进去
Then the JavaScript part could say,
而 JavaScript 负责的就是
when someone hovers their mouse over this text,
当有人把鼠标停在文字上面时
I want it to turn blue.
我想要它变成蓝色
So that we would use JavaScript to do because that the functionality.
这时我们就可以使用 JavaScript 来实现这个功能
These things work together so well and there are endless possibilities.
它们结合起来非常好 有无数的可能结果
Let's keep exploring some more.
让我们接着探索更多内容吧